<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Basics on The Flow</title><link>/road-freight/basics/</link><description>Recent content in Basics on The Flow</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Lei Ma</copyright><atom:link href="/road-freight/basics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What is Road Freight</title><link>/road-freight/basics/what-is-road-freight/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/road-freight/basics/what-is-road-freight/</guid><description>Movements of people, goods and information have always been fundamental components of human societies.
&amp;ndash; J. P. Rodrigue, C. Comtois, and B. Slack, The geography of transport systems. 2006.
A large part of human civilization is to move materials around. Many have played or have been playing their own parts in this great tradition and road transportation is one of the most important modes.
source: undraw.co</description></item><item><title>Modes of Freight</title><link>/road-freight/basics/freight-modes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/road-freight/basics/freight-modes/</guid><description>Road freight is easily spotted in our daily life. As discussed in What is Road Freight, road freight can make up a dominating fraction of freight transportation in some countries such as Malta. However, other modes of transportation are also key to the material flow.
Characteristics of the Transportation Modes Road Freight Rail Freight Water Ways Ocean Freight Air Freight Speed Fast Fast Slow Slow Fast Capacity Small Large Large Large Small Price Low Low Low Low High Environmental Impact High Low Low Low High Coverage High Low Low Low Low Each mode has its own use cases.</description></item><item><title>The Origin-Destination Matrix</title><link>/road-freight/basics/origin-destination-matrix/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/road-freight/basics/origin-destination-matrix/</guid><description>In this section, we will be looking into the so-called origin-destination matrix, or the OD matrix. The OD matrix tells us the trip distribution between a pair of locations $(p, q)$. There are many representations of the OD matrix. It can be represented using a matrix, a network, or the generating process behind it.
Notations
In this page, we will use the following notations.
$P$: a set of origins; $p$: an element of $P$, i.</description></item></channel></rss>