<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Basics on The Flow</title><link>/tags/basics/</link><description>Recent content in Basics on The Flow</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Lei Ma</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/basics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Some Daily Jargons in Road Freight</title><link>/road-freight/topics/road-freight-jargons/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/road-freight/topics/road-freight-jargons/</guid><description>Vehicles Dry van Dry van is very popular on the roads of Europe.1 It is fully enclosed. Dry van is also called box trailer as it looks like a box.
Dry VanSource Moving 2-002 Elf (6th) Short dry van @ Wiki Commons
Flatbed As the name indicates, it is flat.2
FlatbedSource Flatbed @ Wiki Commons
Curtainside The side is a curtain and is very easy to load and unload.</description></item><item><title>Freight Forwarding</title><link>/road-freight/topics/freight-forwarding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/road-freight/topics/freight-forwarding/</guid><description>Shipment of goods is a complex process 1.
Shipment LifecycleSource: 2019 Business Profile | DPDHL
It takes a lot of effort to deal with the whole process by the shipper. Thus in the 19th century, freight forwarders were born 2.
Freight forwarding is not just taking care of the transportation from origin to destination, e.g., taking over the goods and place it on the trucks and transport it to the destination.</description></item><item><title>Describe a Location</title><link>/road-freight/basics/describe-geolocations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/road-freight/basics/describe-geolocations/</guid><description>We can use three types of properties to describe a location1:
Site details (is there a ramp? is it on the wrong side of the road?); Accessibility; Socioeconomic environment. The three types of properties of a location.
The site details and the socioeconomic environment is understood by the name. Here we will discuss the accessibility of a location.
Accessibility of a location Accessibility is a very important property of a location.</description></item></channel></rss>