<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Introduction on The Flow</title><link>/tags/introduction/</link><description>Recent content in Introduction on The Flow</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Lei Ma</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/introduction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Some Daily Jargons in Road Freight</title><link>/road-freight/topics/road-freight-jargons/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/road-freight/topics/road-freight-jargons/</guid><description>Vehicles Dry van Dry van is very popular on the roads of Europe.1 It is fully enclosed. Dry van is also called box trailer as it looks like a box.
Dry VanSource Moving 2-002 Elf (6th) Short dry van @ Wiki Commons
Flatbed As the name indicates, it is flat.2
FlatbedSource Flatbed @ Wiki Commons
Curtainside The side is a curtain and is very easy to load and unload.</description></item><item><title>What is Road Freight</title><link>/road-freight/basics/what-is-road-freight/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/road-freight/basics/what-is-road-freight/</guid><description>Movements of people, goods and information have always been fundamental components of human societies.
&amp;ndash; J. P. Rodrigue, C. Comtois, and B. Slack, The geography of transport systems. 2006.
A large part of human civilization is to move materials around. Many have played or have been playing their own parts in this great tradition and road transportation is one of the most important modes.
source: undraw.co</description></item><item><title>Freight Forwarding</title><link>/road-freight/topics/freight-forwarding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/road-freight/topics/freight-forwarding/</guid><description>Shipment of goods is a complex process 1.
Shipment Lifecycle It takes a lot of effort to deal with the whole process by the shipper. Thus in the 19th century, freight forwarders were born 2.
Freight forwarding is not just taking care of the transportation from origin to destination, e.g., taking over the goods and place it on the trucks and transport it to the destination. It cares about the whole lifecycle of the shipment3 4 5.</description></item><item><title>Modes of Freight</title><link>/road-freight/basics/freight-modes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/road-freight/basics/freight-modes/</guid><description>Road freight is easily spotted in our daily life. As discussed in What is Road Freight, road freight can make up a dominating fraction of freight transportation in some countries such as Malta. However, other modes of transportation are also key to the material flow.
Characteristics of the Transportation Modes Road Freight Rail Freight Water Ways Ocean Freight Air Freight Speed Fast Fast Slow Slow Fast Capacity Small Large Large Large Small Price Low Low Low Low High Environmental Impact High Low Low Low High Coverage High Low Low Low Low Each mode has its own use cases.</description></item><item><title>Economics</title><link>/projects/economics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/economics/</guid><description>In this chapter, we will explore the basics of economics.</description></item><item><title>Road Freight</title><link>/projects/road-freight/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/road-freight/</guid><description>In this chapter, we will explore the basics of road freight.</description></item></channel></rss>